ARIF HUSSAIN

CONTACT

Al Haditah, Saudi Arab 77653

Mobile: +966-573483682

hussainarif1996tit@gmail.com

EDUCATION

2019

Bachelor of Engineering: Mechanical Engineering **Rajiv Gandhi**, Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya, M. GPA: 7.07

2014 Intermediate **BSEB Patna Bihar**, Patna

2012

Matriculation: General **BSEB Patna Bihar**, Patna

LANGUAGES

English

Intermediate

Hindi

Native

Arabic

Beginner

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Applied Mechanical Engineer With a bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering and three years field experience in piping, firefighting & fire alarm . Goal is to hit the position where can take the crucial decisions of organization with experience & ideas. Willing to work as a key player in a challenging & creative environment.

WORK HISTORY

January 2023 - Current **Mechanical Site Engineer**, *K.S.A*, *Saudi Qessma Company*, Al Haditah, Saudi Arab

- Devolve, Coordinate & monitor all aspects of project on site to get smooth workflow
- Follow 2 week look ahead plan and attain weekly meeting
- Supervision of team to achieve target as per project schedule
- Report writing Daily site progress reports, weekly report, WIR & MIR
- Prepare material delivery request to purchase departments as per drawing requirement
- Examine existing utility as built drawing & blueprint to best update and maintain project records
- Installation of all types of pipes on site as per required shop drawing like HDPE, black steel, sprinkler, FHC, ZCV, PRV, Waste cone, NRV, gate valve
- Installation of different types of flanges and valves
- Good knowledge of fire Gas suppression system like FM200
- Knowledge of standard codes like ASTM, NFPA
- Follow of all slandered codes before installation Responsible for installation of gent fire alarm systems Knowledge of different types of pipes used in industry and construction and theirs slandered with codes.

January 2022 - December 2022 **Site Engineer**, *M.T.C. Pvt Ltd*

- General responsible of all work on site related to firefighting & system worked on high rise building project
- Good knowledge of fire Gas suppression system like FM200
- Implementation of work as per approved shop drawing with project specification
- Daily job assigned to foreman and technician to achieve target as per work schedule plan
- Installation of firefighting pipe network including underground and

- above ground, Fire hose cabinet, fire hydrant, water sprinkler with following up shop drawing zone control valve, hydro pressure test for network
- Daily give update to project manager of site progress
- Basic knowledge of NFPA codes, pipe schedule as per NFPA 13, knowledge of sprinkler head distribution, knowledge of black steel pipe detail ASTM A-53, knowledge of inspection of but welding fitting, Knowledge of sprinkler density & area, discharge characteristics, different types of sprinkler head, classes of occupancy & knowledge of different types of hazards.
- · Submission of WIR, MIR
- Familiar with wet riser, dry riser, non-interlock pre action system, single interlock, double interlock pre action system Knowledge of different types of fire hydrants, different types of water flow in pump Knowledge of different types of water pump familiar & measurements of different types of pipe and sizes like OD, NPS with vernier scale Knowledge different types of sprinklers and its uses as per temperature Installation of different types of fire extinguisher Familiar with equipment used in pump room
- Make as built drawing as per site requirement.
- Minimized project risks, conducting structural monitoring to ensure maximum safety and stability.

August 2019 - December 2021 Mechanical Supervisor, Construction and engineering Pvt. Ltd

- Supervision of pipe fabrication of different pipes i.e., stainless steel & allow steel
- Good knowledge of welding, supervision of fittings
- Hydro testing of pipes and pneumatic test Making sure of all safety precaution are taken
- · Daily job assigned to technicians
- Daily give site progress report to site in charge
- Ensure pipe fitting, edge preparation fit of pipe, welding quality of joints
- Inspection of work to adhere to strict to quality maintain
- Good knowledge of piping isometric drawings Good knowledge of visual inspection of welding Performed pipe welding test by NDT Team (DPT,MPT)
- Professional Experience (Indian)
- Personal skill
- · Personal Details
- · Academic Training
- Plan work as per site requirement
- Analyzed equipment and initiated best maintenance practices for enhanced operational reliability
- Performing general machine and building repairs and maintenance, and minor electrical work
- · Academic Projects
- MINI PROJECT

- Maintenance of 3KW roof top power plant
- MINOR PROJECT
- Fabrication of solar distillation unit

SKILLS

- MS-Excel, MS-Word, AutoCAD
- 2D, primavera P6
- Team player & leadership skills.
- Self-motivated &o work under pressure.
- High energetic & hard work responsibility

INTERESTS

HOBBIES, Swimming Visit new place.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Religion: